Dora Sofia Parnanen

As a **Designer** I exercise an open-minded perspective, aware that answers and patterns will reveal themselves when I look and listen closely. Mindful research gives me the power to understand the people and industries around me. Inclusive design is a way for me to advocate for users who aren't in the position I am in to design the experiences.

☐ dorasofia.com ☐ ddorasofia@gmail.com ☐ linkedin.com/in/doraparnanen

Skills

Design: Sketch, Invision, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, HTML & CSS (familiar), Optimising images for web, Static & animated ad banners

UX: User stories, Gliffy user flows, Sketch, Invision, User and consumer habit interviews, Market and competitor research, Client presentations.

Video: Premiere, After Effects (familiar), Storyboarding

Languages: English (fluent), Finnish (fluent) & Spanish (familiar)

Experience

Designer

Luxus Worldwide (2017-current, Helsinki & New York)

At Luxus we work directly with our client, a large consumer electronics company, to produce marketing materials and maintain a consumerfacing website. I coordinate with our several Luxus PMs, copywriter, and developers to create campaign pages, email announcements, market localisations to the website, and static and animated ad banners. I've advocated for diverse representation in our designs' imagery, text readability, and increased flexibility from a CMS standpoint. I work with our developers to optimise assets for web, and to support with Arabic right-to-left website and ad banner layouts. We work within our client's branding and co-branding guidelines to turn local market requests into designs that meet the client's global, corporate approval process and timelines.

UX/UI Designer

Perpetual Solutions (2016, New York)

At Perpetual I was able to take on entire phases of client work, and I worked with our other designer for any hand-overs and client coordination. My main project was for a large media corporation client, rethinking their existing internal employee tool. I conducted research and recorded user interviews at the client's corporate office in Times Square, listening for user paint points and task goals. I later tested the MVP prototype with employees. I was able to advocate for the internal tool to come to use familiar terms and shift away from its technical-heavy focus.

Education

BA in Design Media Arts

UCLA (2012-2016)

I developed my visual style and focus on message, using these to explore new interfaces such as interactive video installation, print layout and bookmaking, and digital and physical game design.

Minor in Digital Humanities

UCLA (2014-2016)

I incorporated behavioral, research based learning from courses in Anthropology, Sociology, and Information Studies.

Film Production, English, and Graphic Design classes

Freestyle Academy of Communication Arts and Technology (2010–2012)

I co-produced, cast, directed, and edited a Narrative film that was selected and shown at our end of year student showcase for the community.

Experience

	□ ddorasofia@gmail.com
Dogtown Media (2016, Los Angeles)	_
dorasofia.com	∠ linkedin.com/in/doraparnanen
At Dogtown I worked with our long list of clients both one-on-one and with our team of Senior Researcher, UI Designers, Developer, and Business leads in a collaborative, mentorship environment. My role included market and user insights, user flows, wireframing for mobile apps and web, user interviews, UI directions and application, and developer hand-off. We frequently presented research and design deliverables to clients. I learned that for clients who are startups themselves, it is important to clearly outline the design-to-launch process and scope of work, introduce the client to UX deliverables and what is expected of all involved on the project, and to validate any research or designs with user quotes and market best practices.	
Idean (2014 & 2015, Palo Alto)	
dorasofia.com	
During my first summer as Interaction Design Intern, I was immersed in a client project, ideating alongside our tight-knit team of PM, UX Designer, Developer, and client. When I returned the following summer I had a solo project to create any interface that could provide business value to Idean. I interviewed Idean's designers to gain insight into their common practices and painpoints, and found an opportunity to lessen employee time and clicks spent navigating to relevant information.	
Strategic Planning and Research	
Bruin Advertising & Marketing Team (2015–2016, UCLA)	
2nd Place at the National Student Advertising Competition (NSAC) 2016 Southern California Regionals	
dorasofia.com	
At this student-run advertising agency we had the task of creating a marketing campaign for the following 2017 year to grow Snapple™ in the US, measured by brand relevance, purchase frequency, and brand awareness. On the Strategic Planning subcommittee we researched actionable insights about our consumers, competitive landscape, and brand history. We hosted user focus groups and targeted street interviews, and directly involved Ad Team's other subcommittees in the process. This allowed us to create a campaign strategy from narratives we all came to understand.	
Freelance Designer	
dorasofia.com	

Assistant Teacher

Finnish Language School of Silicon Valley (2008–2012)

After graduating myself, I joined as assistant to a class of elementary aged students. I encouraged Finnish language and communication skills through interactive class activity and homework review.

dorasofia.com